不是个好主意
Nope.
有人吗
Hello?
本 艾莉
Ben? Alex?
嘿
Whoa, whoa! Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey.
好吧
Okay.
别这样
Stop. Stop!
好 嘿 别激动
All right, hey. Hey, take it easy.
行了
All right.
你们是什么人
- Who are you?
别给我装傻 你在机车里干什么
- Don't play dumb. What were you doing in the Engine?
你的麻烦大了
- You're in a lot of trouble.
嘿 别
- Hey. Hey, hey, hey. No, no, no. Hey. Hey. Hey, hey.
听着 我不知道你们…
Listen, I don't know what you--
各位好啊
- Hello, chaps.
糟糕
- Shit.
不要 嘿 老天
Hey! Jesus!
安德烈 刚才好险啊 搜他身
- That was too close, Andre. Clean him up.
-哈维  -是的
- Javi? - Yeah.
-你拿到了吗  -拿到什么
- Have you got it? - Got what?
鲁丝
Ruth?
闭嘴 别破坏气氛
- Oh, shut up. - You're ruining this.
-嗯 在他身上 -很好
- Yeah. He's got it. - Good.
-撤吧 这会招来麻烦的 -冷静点
- Come on. Let's clear out. - This'll draw heat. - Calmly now. Calmly.
我们分头行动 在边境汇合 所有人都带着过境文件吧
We split up and meet at the border. Everybody got their papers?
-带着 -很好 来吧 我们走
- Yeah. - Good. Come on. Let's go.
-鲁丝 -走吧
- Okay. Let's go.
什么
- What?
怎么回事
What the...
温妮
Winnie?
有何不可呢
Why not?
真不错
Yeah.
提尔 好
Till. Wow. Okay.
嘿 你得帮帮我 我需要…
Hey, you gotta help me. I need--
小声点
Inside voices.
这场噩梦已经做得够久了 我得醒过来
Yeah, that's about enough of this nightmare. I have to wake up.
嘿 伙计 你得打起精神 好吗
- Hey, buddy, you gotta get your shit together, okay?
你不是在做梦
You're not dreaming.
而是快死了
You're dying.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
黎明了 守夜结束
- It's first light. - The vigil's over.
我们把他叫出来吧
- Let's go get our boy.
雷顿
- Layton.
Layton.
雷顿
- Layton.
他的脉搏很弱 去找裴尔顿医生 快去
- His pulse is weak. - Go and get Dr. Pelton. Quick, quick, go.
好
Okay. Okay.
雷顿 醒醒
Layton, wake up.
快醒醒
Wake up.
醒醒
- Wake up. Wake up.
-嘿 -醒过来
- Hey. - Wake up. - Hey.
嘿 冷静点 否则你会害我们俩都进大牢的
Cool it, or you'll get us both thrown in the slammer.
在这里你不能胡来 明白吗
You can't mess around here, okay?
“这里”是哪里
- Where is here?
这里是雪国列车
- This is Snowpiercer.
-这不是雪国列车 -这里是 但也不是
- This is not Snowpiercer. - No, it is. And it isn't.
你会认出这里的人 但他们跟那一边的不一样
You'll recognize people, but they're not the same as they are over there.
你几乎是一样的
- You're the same. Sort of.
我是图书管理员 我很博学
- I'm the librarian. I know things.
你身上还带着另一边的残留物 但它们会退去的
You're still carrying residue from the other side. But it will fade.
你会习惯这里的
- You'll get used to it here.
习惯 不 提尔 我得回家去
- No. "Used to it"? No. Till, I need to get home.
回家 那就不同了
- Oh. Well, that's different.
-那事儿我帮不上忙 -为什么
I don't think I can help you with that. - Why not?
首先 你得去见末等车厢老大
Well, first, you'd have to see the Tail Boss.
但去那的路上很危险 明白我的意思吗
But that's a dangerous journey, you know want I'm saying?
不明白
- Nope, I don't.
好吧 听好了
- Okay. Work with me.
如果你想回去 就得找到末等车厢
If you want to get back, you need to find the Tail
求末等车厢老大把你送回去
and ask the Tail Boss to send you home.
威尔福德 他刚才假装是我的朋友
Wilford, he was pretending to be my buddy
他打算越过边境处理什么事务
and he was gonna cross the border for some mission,
但我需要过境文书
but I needed papers.
-这个我能帮上忙 -好
- Oh. Now, that I can help you with. - Okay.
-跟我来 -好
- Follow me. - Yes.
可以了
- Got it.
好 数到三 一 二 三
- Okay, on three. One, two, three.
他怎么样了 医生怎么说
- How is he? Well, what does the doctor say?
暂时没消息 医生此刻跟雷顿在一起 我们刚把他送来
- Nothing yet. - She's with him now. We only just got here.
你之前说不会有事的
You said everything was gonna be fine.
乔西 发生什么事了
- Josie. What happened?
我也不知道 这…
- I don't know.
我们…怎么都叫不醒他
He just--he just wouldn't wake up.
赝造师就在下一扇门里
The forger's the next door down.
-别让他知道你不是这里的人 -你不一起来吗
Don't let on you're not from here. - You're not coming?
雷顿 我没法带你去末等车厢 听我说
I can't get you to the Tail, Layton. Listen to me.
你在这里的时间越长 回另一边去的难度就越大
The longer you're here, the harder it is to get to the other side.
别迷路了
Do not get lost.
你这是干什么
- What did you do that for?
你在阳世的时间不多了
You don't have much time in the real world.
如果你开始迷路 这个伤口会给你指路
This cut will guide you if you start to lose your way.
我该谢谢你
- Thanks, I guess.
好了 祝你好运 伙计 你会需要的
- Okay. Good luck, bud. You'll need it.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
是你
It's you.
-我需要过境文书 -别在走廊里说这个
- Uh, I'm here for my papers. - Not in the hall. - Not in the hall.
你想来一杯吗
- You want one?
不用了 谢谢
- No, thanks.
很好
- Good.
（临时旅行证）
开始让你厌烦了吧
Starts to wear on you, doesn't it?
编的故事说多了
You tell yourself your cover story
自己都开始忘记什么是真的 什么是编的了
so many times, you start to forget what's real and what you made up.
我可不这么认为
- I don't know about that.
你从没相信过自己编的谎言
You never started to believe your own lie?
随便吧 你无需向我证明你自己
Whatever, you don't have to prove yourself to me.
我已经退出江湖了
I am out of the game.
这只是一份让我坚持下去的小小副业
This is just a little side hustle to keep me going.
在这里签字
Sign here.
-有了这个 我就能去末等车厢  -末等车厢
- This will get me in the Tail? - The Tail?
怎么 你想寻死吗
- What, you got a death wish?
事实上恰恰相反
Uh, just the opposite, actually.
我可不掺和末等车厢的事
Well, I don't mess with the Tail.
明白吗
You understand?
如果你想去末等车厢 就得去找制图师
You want the Tail, go see the Cartographer.
制图师
- Cartographer?
没错 去市场找
- Yes. In the Market.
我需要一些东西作为回报
I'm gonna need something in return.
有两名特工在列车前列遇害
Two operatives got whacked uptrain.
我听说你参与了此事
I heard that you were involved,
但我觉得扣动扳机的另有其人
but I figure someone else pulled the trigger.
所以…
So...
你把开枪的人的名字告诉我 我就把过境文书给你
you give me the triggerman's name, and I will send you on your way.
我不知道 知道我也不做告密的小人
I don't know, and I don't rat.
文书你留着吧
Keep your damn papers.
鲁丝 这里是怎么回事
What's going on here, Ruth?
只是个小小的考验 你之前搞砸了 被人抓了
- Just a little test. You screwed up and got caught.
-我们得确认是否还能信任你 -你有答案了
We need to know we can trust you. - You have your answer.
我会盯着你的
- I got my eye on you.
有消息吗
- Any news?
没有
- No.
他情况稳定 你们可以进去看他了
- He's stable. - You can see him now.
这事没有委婉的表达方法
Well, there's no sugarcoating this.
他处于昏迷中 已经长达12小时
He's in a coma, has been for up to 12 hours already.
他会醒过来吗
- Will he wake up?
真希望我能回答你
- I wish I could tell you.
CT扫描显示脑部有些肿胀
CT scan shows some brain swelling,
但他的瞳孔有反应 这是个好迹象
but his pupils are responding, so that's a good sign.
那我们现在要怎么办
- So what do we do now?
保持坚强
Stay strong,
握着他的手 跟他说说话
hold his hand, talk to him.
恐怕除了等待 没其他办法
It's a waiting game, I'm afraid,
但欢迎你们留下来
but you're welcome to stay.
我得走了
- I gotta go.
有消息及时通知我们
- You keep us updated.
好的
- Yeah.
我得回机车了
I have to get back to the Engine.
好
- Yeah.
我也去
- Yeah. I'll come too.
你没必要离开 他会希望你留在这里
- You don't have to. He'd want you here.
你确定吗
- Are you sure?
确定
- Yeah.
他通过考验了
- He passed.
暂时而已
- So far.
我当然通过考验了
- Course I passed.
兄弟 我跟她说你很靠谱
I told her you were solid, sport.
别让我失望
- Don't let me down.
好 我准备好了 我们走吧
- Yeah. I'm good. - Let's go.
好 我们一个一个地过境
- Right. We cross the border individually.
回答问题时只用“是”或“不是”
Answer questions yes or no.
只要伪装的身份不穿帮 就不会有事
Stick to your cover stories. We should be good.
好吗 我们走
All right? Let's go.
好
- All right.
嘿 我的伪装身份是什么
- Hey. - Uh, what's my cover story?
你是开玩笑吗
- You joking?
不是 我只是忘了
- No, I'm fine. I just forgot.
行事谨慎些
- Well, tighten up.
你是个舞者
- You're a dancer.
姓名
- Name?
-约瑟夫威尔福德 -此行的目的
- Joseph Wilford. - Purpose of travel?
（现代舞表演 晚上8点）
进出口 外国水果和糖品
- Import-export. - Exotic fruit and sugars.
谢谢
Thank you.
姓名
- Name?
安德烈雷顿
- Andre Layton.
姓名
- Name?
-我刚…安德烈雷顿 -你为什么会来列车前列
- I just--Andre Layton. - Why were you uptrain?
我是个舞者
- I'm a dancer.
我喜欢芭蕾
- I love the ballet.
不 其实我是跳现代舞的
- No, it's modern, actually.
我们有演出
We had a recital.
舞蹈是身体及灵魂…隐藏的语言
Dance is the hidden language of the body...and soul.
可惜我错过了
- Sad I missed it.
下一次呗
- Next time.
嗨
Hello?
你不该在这里的
You shouldn't be in here.
我知道 我只是想静一下
- Well, I'm just hiding out.
但我可以离开
But I--I can leave.
这地方都是你的了
It's all yours.
我听说雷顿的事了
I heard about Layton.
-我很难过 -你会难过才怪
I'm very sorry. - Yeah, I'm sure you are.
我以前从没见你哭过
I've never seen you cry before.
你不用强忍住伤心
You know, you don't have to fight it.
他是你最好的朋友
He was your best friend.
他现在这样 我却无能为力
And there's nothing I can do to help him.
所以 你走吧 奥德丽
So--bye, Audrey.
你可以跟他说说话
- You could talk to him.
如果他的意识还在就能听到
If he's still in there, he'll hear you.
你说什么
- And say what?
提醒他他为之奋斗的是什么
Remind him what he's fighting for.
这事应该你来
- You should do it.
我
- Me?
就像你以前在夜车做的那样
Like you used to in the Nightcar.
你能影响他人的想法和感受
You get inside people's heads.
这是你的专长
That's your thing.
这跟那个不一样
- This is different.
你刚才还说值得一试呢
You just told me it's worth a try.
求你了…奥德丽
Please, Audrey.
老约 鲁丝
- Joe. Ruthie.
你们来这里我太高兴了
Oh, you have just made my day.
快下来
Get down here right now.
我们只是顺路拜访
- We're just dropping in.
休息一下 来吧 伙计们
Brief respite. Come on, chaps.
我亲爱的 你真是光彩照人呀
You, my dear, are radiant.
是因为湿润 让皮肤变得有光泽
- It is the humidity. - It makes me glow.
你们能在这里待多久  我留着你最喜欢的桌位呢
Now, how long do I get to keep you? Come, I've got your favorite table waiting.
至少到傍晚时分吧
Till the sun's over the yard, at least.
嘿 过来吧 来呀
- Hey, hey. - Come here.
请给我们两杯烈酒
Two shots, please.
你忘了礼节了吧
- You forgot your manners.
三杯
Three shots.
这是朗姆酒
- That's rum.
那还用说 有问题吗
- No shit. That a problem?
不 只是…让我想起了往事
No, it just, um, takes me back.
你看看
- Oh. Check it.
看着不错
- Looks good.
鲁丝
- Ruth.
我要去一下洗手间
I'm gonna go to the restroom.
嘿 稍等一下 我们聊聊
- Hey, wait a minute. - Let's have a chat.
鲁丝 看在老天的份上 让他喘口气吧 抱歉了 老伙计
- For God's sake, Ruth. - Let him breathe. Sorry, old chap.
再来一杯朗姆酒
- Another rum.
你好
你好 我在找制图师
Hey, I'm looking for the cartographer.
-来顶帽子吧 -好 谢谢
Uh, yeah, thank you.
这帽子很不错
- It's a good one.
你迷路了吗
- Are you lost?
你就是制图师
- You're the cartographer?
没错 进来吧
- Yeah. Come in.
干吗盯着我看
You're staring.
抱歉 你让我想起了一个人
- Yeah. Sorry. - You remind me of someone.
-你想去哪儿  -末等车厢
- Where you trying to go? - The Tail.
为什么想去那儿
- Why you want to go there?
回到我的家人身边
- Get back to my family.
是吗 你有孩子
- Yeah? You're a dad?
我们有个女儿
- We have a daughter.
当了父母 你就会做出疯狂的事来
Yeah, well, being a parent makes you do crazy things.
好
- Okay.
是这样…到末等车厢那里去不是难事
So getting to the Tail, that's the easy part.
但是要进去 就得知道暗号
Getting in the Tail, you need the word.
好吧 暗号是什么
- Okay. What's the word?
我不知道暗号是什么 不过 “多数人会避开 有些人会寻求
- I don't know the word, but..."Most will run, some will seek.
不管是躲是骗 你我总会邂逅
"Hide or cheat, we always meet.
我把当下 过去和未来守候”
I present, past and future keep."
这是个谜语吗 我讨厌猜谜
- Is that a riddle? - Oh, I hate riddles. - Okay, that's enough.
-够了 -再说一遍
- Give it to me again. - That's enough.
嘿 好吧
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Okay.
嘿
Just let go of my arm. Man! Hey!
交给你们了
- Gracias. - All yours.
好吧
Okay.
我跟你说不能相信他吧
- I told you he stunk.
-别激动 我只是有点私事要办 -理由不够充分
Easy, okay? I just had some personal business. Oh, you're gonna have to do better than that, man.
你搞砸了取货的事 忘了自己的密码
You botched the pick-up, you forgot your password,
而且我知道 你跟赝造师谈过末等车厢的事
and I know that you talked to the Forger earlier about the Tail.
我替你做了担保 你告诉我说不会瞎问问题的
- I vouched for you, Andre. You told me you wouldn't ask any questions.
我只是在保护自己
- I was just covering my back.
干了他得了 我们冒不起这种风险
- Let's pop him. We can't risk this shit.
把这玩意拿开 叫他们退下
- Get that shit out of my face. You tell them to stand down.
你需要我
You need me,
-否则你不会带我到这里来 -我们只需要你安排会面的事
or you never would've brought me this far. We only need you for the meeting, Andre.
那之后你我就两不相干了 明白吗
After that, we're done. Do you understand?
-我没问题 -鲁丝 把枪放下
- Fine by me. - Put the gun down, Ruth.
你不知道的事可能会伤害到你
What you don't know might hurt you.
他们没有问题 艾莉
- They're okay, Alex.
就他一个
Just him.
把他带过来
Bring him down.
看看呀 他出现了
Look at that, he showed up.
可不是 计划不就是这样的吗
- That was the plan, right?
闭嘴
- Shut up.
嘿 我们该客气点
Hey, we're gonna be friends here, maybe.
你好吗
How you doing?
-见到你真高兴 -我也是
Good to see you. - You too.
嘿 你饿吗 你总是喊饿
- Hey. You hungry? You're always hungry.
我们给你弄点蟹螯吧 给这边来点蟹螯 蟹腿和牡蛎
Hey, let's get you some claws. Some claws, some legs, oysters over here.
牡蛎和蟹螯 马上来
- Oysters, claws, coming up.
坐
- Have a seat.
好
- All right. Uh...
-山姆… -这位…山姆…
- Sam. - This is--Sam,
-这是约瑟夫威尔福德 -叫老约
this is Joseph Wilford. - Joe.
老约 这位就是我跟你提起的人
- Joe. This is the guy I was telling you about.
你没事吧
- You all right?
我们很快会知道的
- I guess we'll see.
来了
- Here we go.
开吃吧
- Go ahead. Dive in.
我不是来这里吃海鲜或找人作伴的
- I'm not really here for the seafood or the company.
螃蟹是肮脏的生物
The crab's a filthy creature.
他曾警告过我 说我不会喜欢你
He warned me I wouldn't like you.
他也是这么跟我说的 老伙计
He said the same about you, old chap,
但我告诉他这并不重要 反正我会忘记你的
but I told him it doesn't really matter, 'cause I'll forget you, anyway.
我听说了列车前列的枪击事件 两名特工被杀 这对这笔买卖很不利
I heard about that heat uptrain. Two dead G-men. That kind of sours the deal.
那事怨我 现场没有目击证人
- Oh, hey, that's on me. There were no witnesses.
是老约帮我摆脱了困境
Joe bailed me out.
让我们顺利过了边境
Got us across the border clean.
只要我要的东西能到手 我不在乎这些
Well, it's not my problem, as long as I get what I need.
我们来检查一下吧
- Let's have a look. Shall we?
很正宗
- It's legit.
对 没问题
- Yeah. It's all good.
很好
- Good.
凭我被赋予的权力 你们几个混蛋被捕了
- By the power vested in me, you assholes are under arrest.
不 别这样 不要
No! No, don't shoot!
上
- Go.
起来
- Get up.
现代舞表演
Modern dance recital?
那是个儿童舞蹈团
That was the kids' troupe.
我们走
Let's go.
你现在麻烦大了
You're in a world of trouble now.
你还真是跟那边的你一模一样
- Why am I not surprised you're like this over here too?
行刑安排在午夜
- Firing squad's at midnight.
等等 行刑
- Wait. Hey, hey. - Firing squad?
保重
- Take care.
你想获得宽恕吗
- Do you want forgiveness?
派克
- Pike?
上帝啊
Oh, God.
确实如此 兄弟 你的大限快到了
- Indeed, brother. Your hour draws nigh.
承认你的罪孽 你就会获得宽恕
Confess your sins, and you will be absolved.
什么罪孽
- Of what?
餐厅里有一堆尸体 就从这事开始吧
There are a pile of bodies in the cantina. Start there.
我只是想回家
I just want to go home.
如果你都不知道
- How can you get back home
自己在找的是什么 你要怎么回家呢
if you don't even know what you're looking for?
末等车厢老大能送我回家
The Tail Boss can send me home.
这一点你就大错特错了
That's where you're very wrong.
你究竟想要我做什么
What do you really want from me?
你当时威胁到了新伊甸园
You threatened New Eden.
我别无选择 派克
I didn't have any choice, Pike.
愿上帝怜悯你的灵魂
May God have mercy on your soul.
不 派克 我赢了
- No. Pike. Pike, I won.
我有资格保守我的秘密 派克  这是说好的事
I get to keep my secrets, Pike! That was the deal!
派克
Pike!
他的情况如何
- How's he doing?
没有好转
- No change.
她来这里干什么
What is she doing here?
我明白 扎拉 但你跟着她在夜车做过
- Oh. I know, Zarah. But you worked with her in the Nightcar.
你知道她的能耐
You know what she can do.
我不知道是否会有效果 但我可以试试
I don't know if it'll work, but I can try.
反正没有坏处
- Guess it couldn't hurt.
-我可以去歇口气 -是呀
- I could use a break. - Yeah.
乔西 你想去喝杯咖啡吗
Josie, want to get a cup of coffee?
好的
- Yeah, sure.
好 现在要怎么做
- Okay. Now what happens?
-我试着跟他沟通 -好 开始吧
- I try to reach him. - Okay. Let's go.
安德烈
- Andre.
你听
Listen.
听听自己的呼吸声
Listen to your breath.
感受空气随着每一个呼吸 进出于你的肺部
Feel the in and out as the air fills your lungs.
安德烈 如果你能听到我说话
Andre, if you can hear me,
就朝我的声音过来
move towards my voice.
回想你身体的感觉
Remember your body.
回想女儿在你怀里的感觉
The feel of your daughter in your arms.
回想你爱的人在你耳边低语的感觉
Someone you love whispering in your ear.
回想你自己的样子
Remember yourself.
你在寻找一样东西
You're searching for something
但你不知道具体是什么
but you don't know what.
安德烈 你被困住了
You're trapped, Andre.
你在抓着不真实的东西不肯放手
You're holding onto something that isn't real.
到我这里来
Move towards me.
回来吧
Come back.
不管拖住你的东西是什么…去面对它
Whatever's keeping you here, face it.
然后回家
And come home.
安德烈 你来了
Andre. You made it.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
我在出去的时候中了一枪
I caught a bullet on the way out.
你得继续前进
You've got to keep going.
什么意思
- What do you mean?
去末等车厢 你就快到了
- To the Tail. You're nearly there.
给
Here.
拿着
Take it.
这是什么
- What is it?
是我们给末等车厢老大的礼物
It's our gift to the Tail Boss.
祝好运
Good luck.
我熟悉你这样子
- I recognize this.
这说明你对某个想法着了迷
You've glommed on to some theory.
这是第一步 “疯狂地研究”
This is step one, "research frenzy."
第二步会是“浸泡在浴缸里” 如果你有浴缸的话
Step two would be "soak in the bathtub" if you had one.
-好了 怎么回事  -或许其实没事
- So what is it? - Could be nothing.
你肯定有所发现 否则你不会叫我过来
- Well, it's clearly something because you called me in here.
艾莉 我需要航图
- I need charts, Alex.
还有我的工具 平行尺 指南针
And my instruments-- parallel ruler, compass.
好用来割破看守的喉咙
So that you can slash your guard in the throat?
雷顿先生真的生命垂危吗
Is it true Mr. Layton is at death's door?
这你不需要知道
- That's need-to-know.
行 政治的事我不掺和
- Fine. Leave me out of the politics.
但这个…这是重大发现 艾莉
But this...this is big, Alex.
能给大家真正的希望 尤其是你
Give everyone some real hope, especially you.
如果你不帮我…
If you don't help me,
就可能永远都不会知道了
we may never know.
老伊凡的方法
- Old Ivan's Way.
我很抱歉
- I'm sorry.
本不该走到对决这一步的
It wasn't supposed to go to knives.
老天 我痛恨末等车厢
- God, I hated the Tail.
所有那些习俗
- All of its customs.
比如把上下铺当钢琴弹
Like people playing the piano like it wasn't a bunk bed.
与此同时 安德烈会教孩子们 如何繁殖老鼠 好当我们的食物
Meanwhile, Andre's teaching children how to breed rats just so we can eat.
我们在那度过了一些黑暗的日子
- Oh, we had some dark times.
是呀
- Yeah.
但是 你和安德烈 把大家照顾得非常好
But you know, you and Andre took such good care of everyone.
你们俩 你们…
I mean, the two of you just--
你们能激发出对方最好的一面
you really bring out the best in each other.
这我可不确定
- I don't know.
真的
- You do.
这一点曾让我深受威胁 可现在不会了
You know, it used to really threaten me, but it doesn't anymore.
比起当情侣 我和安德烈更适合合作当父母
Andre and I are better as co-parents than as a couple.
乔西…
Josie...
我不该出卖你的 我…
I never should have turned my back on you. I--
嘿 你当时受到胁迫 别无选择
- Hey. You were backed against a wall.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
从没怪过你
Never have.
今天有你在这里陪着我 我很高兴 我…
I'm just so glad you're here with me today. I...
我也很高兴安德烈能有你作伴
And I'm glad that Andre has you too.
有人吗
Hello?
什么事
- What do you want?
乔西
- Josie.
抱歉
Sorry...
你是末等车厢老大吗
you're the Tail Boss?
你没回答我的问题
You didn't answer my question.
别 嘿…
- No. Hey.
我叫安德烈雷顿 我想回家
- My name is Andre Layton, and I'm trying to get back home.
你认识我吗
Do you know me?
不认识 但末等车厢老大认识每一个人
No, but the Tail Boss knows everyone.
“多数人会避开 有些人会寻求 不管是躲是骗 你我总会邂逅
"Most will run, but some will seek. "But hide or cheat, we'll always meet.
我把当下 过去和未来守候”
I present, past and future keep."
我是谁
- Who am I?
-乔西… -我是谁 雷顿先生
- Josie. - Who am I, Mr. Layton?
死亡
- Death.
我一直在等你 我没想到你会知道暗号
- Been expecting you. Didn't think you'd know the word.
是呀 我…事实上对此非常清楚
- Yeah. I guess. I know it too well, actually.
我想我是在试图逃避死亡
I guess I'm trying to escape it.
死亡不是你的敌人
- Death isn't the enemy.
你来这里是因为你在害怕一件事
You're here 'cause you're scared of something.
哦
- Oh, yeah?
我在害怕什么
What am I afraid of?
我不知道 但你得去面对它
- I don't know, but you're gonna have to face it.
他来了
He's here.
这列车由你统管
- You run the train.
没错
- Yes, I do.
大权在末等车厢 前后颠倒了
- The power's in the Tail. - It's upside-down.
这里没有什么前后
- There's no up, no down.
这列车周而复始 是一个残酷的循环
The train is cyclical. It's a cruel loop.
没错 我看到地图了 是一条衔尾蛇
- Right. - I saw the map. A snake eating its tail.
我要怎么才能跳出这个循环呢
How do I get back out of a loop?
你可以出去了 乔西
- Thank you, Josie.
你喜欢她
You like her.
这事说来复杂
- It's complicated.
这事永远不像看上去那么复杂 带礼物来了吗
It's never as complicated as it seems. You bring me a gift?
我也有东西要给你
I have something for you too.
这是扎拉的笔迹
- That's Zarah's handwriting.
念给我听
- Read it to me.
“我的小心肝…
"My little soul,
虽然我还没见过你的脸 也没有抱过你
"I haven't seen your face yet or held you in my arms,
但我对你的爱早已无穷无尽
"but my love for you is already limitless.
你不光是我的孩子 你还是我们的未来”
You aren't just my child. You're the future."
你是丽雅娜
Liana?
嗨
- Hi.
不 这不是你的未来
No, this is-- this isn't your future.
不是的 为了你 我要回去
It's not. I'm going back for you.
我能把你解救出来 打破这个循环
I--I can get you out of this. I can break the cycle.
看看你给我的礼物是什么吧
- Look at what you brought me.
你来这里不是为了面对自己的大限
You're not here to face your death.
是派克的炸弹
- Pike's bomb.
而是来面对我的大限的
- You're here to face mine.
丽雅娜
- Liana! Liana!
安德烈 醒醒
- Andre. Andre, wake up.
做噩梦了吧
That was a rough one, huh?
阿莎
- Asha?
我怎么会在这里
What am I doing here?
丽雅娜应该把我送回家的呀
Liana was supposed to send me home.
这里就是你的家
- This is your home.
不 我应该在雪国列车上的
No. I'm supposed to be on Snowpiercer.
这地狱就是你唯一的家
This hell is the only home you know.
我快要找到答案了
- I'm close to the answer.
别看那里面
- Don't look in there.
午饭准备好了
Lunch is ready.
番茄汤和烤奶酪
Tomato soup and a grilled cheese.
让我想起了往事
- A memory.
听着 我们不该流连于往事
Look, we shouldn't dwell on the past.
光是设法活下去就够我们操心的了
We've got enough to worry about just trying to stay alive.
那里头是什么
- What's in there?
-你有什么事瞒着我  -安德烈
What are you keeping from me? - Andre.
给我看
- Show me.
-把钥匙给我 -别 不要
Give me the key. - No. No!
-给… -放手
Get off!
阿莎
Asha.
停下 快住手
Stop! Stop it!
里面的东西你不会喜欢的 明白吗
You're not gonna like what you find in there, okay?
是掠夺者
Marauders.
掠夺者 杀死所有人的那些家伙
Marauders? The guys that killed everyone?
-并非都是 但多数是 -可恶
- Not all, but most. - Shit.
阿莎
- Asha!
Asha!
这就是一切开始的地方
- This is where it started,
我第一次看到新伊甸园的地方
where I first saw New Eden.
你不需要看那里头的东西
You don't need to look in there.
你让我别给你看到的
You told me not to let you see it.
（10月）
这是我想象出来的
- I made it up.
安德烈 裴尔顿医生
- Andre. Dr. Pelton!
没事的 你醒了
It's okay, it's okay. You're back.
（《意大利文艺复兴全史》）
嘿
- Hey.
我…我觉得你会想知道一下 裴尔顿医生说他会好起来
I--I thought you'd want to know Dr. Pelton thinks he's gonna be okay.
不会有持久的脑损伤之类的
No lasting brain damage or anything.
所以…
So...
谢谢你…帮了他
thank you for helping him.
你真的是安德烈的好朋友
You're a really good friend to Andre.
贝丝
Bess,
你这么关心别人 却不让别人来关心你
you care so much for other people, but you won't let anyone care for you.
为什么呢
Why is that?
这一天已经很够呛了 奥德丽
- It's been a long day, Audrey.
-谢谢 -嘿
- Oh, thanks. - Hey.
嗨
- Hey.
你把我们吓坏了
You had us scared.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
万一
- What if...
我当时太迫切地想给大家一个未来…
I was so desperate to give everyone a future...
结果就瞎编了一个 那怎么办
that I made one up?
如果我所拥有的只是一个谎言 我无法领导这列车
I can't lead this train if all I have is a lie.
（加拿大）
当初离开阿塔卡马之后 你们走的是哪条路线
After the Atacama, what route did you take?
我不会告诉你的 这是怎么回事
- I'm not telling you that. What is all this?
跟我来
- Come with me.
两列列车分开之后 我跟着你们的踪迹
After our trains separated, I followed your trail,
试图猜测你们的意图
trying to guess intentions,
你们的近期目的地及长远轨迹
near-term destination versus long-term trajectory.
我跟不上你们 所以得半路拦截
I couldn't catch you. I had to intercept.
看到没
See?
好吧
- Whoa, okay.
所以 在三个月之后 我觉得自己有了突破
So about three months in, I thought I caught a break--
在马赛附近探测到了轨道切换的信号
a track switch signal near Marseille.
我们赶到那里 却没发现你们的踪迹
We followed it there but found no sign of you.
是呀 因为我们没在那片大陆上 离法国远着呢
Well, yeah, 'cause that was the wrong continent. We were nowhere near France.
那么问题就来了 如果切换轨道的 不是你们 那会是谁
So the question is, if it wasn't you, who was it?
信号出错
- A signal error.
不 我不认为那是故障引起的 艾莉
No. I don't think it was a malfunction, Alex.
我觉得那是你母亲
I believe it was your mother.
梅兰妮还活着
That Melanie is alive.
字幕翻译：黛拉